Burd-Shippen Papers 1708-1792 Mss.B.B892
American Philosophical Society
- Correspondence, 1740-1792; Series I; 1 lin. foot
  - to James Burd, 1751 June 1; 1p.; Groome, Samuel Jr. (Box 1)
    Turners Creek. Updates on Burd's business affairs.
  - to James Burd, 1751 July 24; 1p.; Wallace, John (Box 1)
    Philadelphia. Letter for an invoice and bill of lading (not included).
  - to James Burd, 1751 July 26; 1p.; McCall, Samuel (Box 1)
    Philadelphia. Letter for bill of lading for shipment.
  - to James Burd, 1751 July 27; 1p.; Hodges, William (Box 1)
    Philadelphia. Bill of loading for bread to be sold in Jamaca.
  - to Walter Sterling, 1752 February 26; 1p.; Burd, James (Box 1)
    Philadelphia. Regarding the building of a ship.
  - to James Burd, 1752 April 29; 2pp.; Stirling, Walter (Box 1)
    Philadelphia. Contacting Burd regarding settling the estate of George Mitchelson, and contracts he had.
  - to James Burd, 1752 August 16; 1p.; Simpson, Thomas (Box 1)
    Has plowirons and plow for him at John Harrises, but not been able to send them.
  - to James Burd, 1752 October 21; 1p.; Rutherford, Thomas (Box 1)
    Reply to Burd regarding coming for cattle and mare for Mr. Shippen.
  - to James Burd, 1752 October 31; 1p.; Blyth, William (Box 1)
    Shippensburg. Request for favor.
  - to Mr. Buerd [sic], 1753 March 26; 1p.; Evans, Simon (Box 1)
    Carlisle. Replies in regards to doing work for Mr. Shippen.
  - to Edward Shippen, 1753 April 27; 1p.; Hamilton, James, 1710-1783 (Box Oversize)
    Burk Hill. Discusses growth of public houses in Lancaster, and advices what he wishes done.
  - to James Burd, 1753 May 16; 1p.; Kidd, John (Box 1)
    Philadelphia. Asks Burd to secure from W. Anderson the money owed to him.
  - to James Hamilton, 1753 September 18; 2pp.; Shippen, Edward (Box 1)
    Carlisle. Quotes Croghan as saying 100 Indians are anxious to get home; treaty with Virginians forthcoming. Indians are coming to Carlisle and the Governor should come too. Freeman and Smith 2845.
  - to James Burd, 1753 December 11; 1p.; Coxe, William (Box 1)
    Philadelphia. Asks Burd to finish the affair with W. Anderson.
  - to James Burd, 1754 April 6; 1p.; Kidd, John (Box 1)
    Philadelphia. Asks Burd's opinion of the Anderson matter, feeling it will turn out bad.
  - Petition of the inhabitants of township of Hopewell to the Court at Carlisle, 1754 April 23; 2pp. (Box 1)
    Regarding the upkeep of a road, and the proposal for a new road.
  - to Edward Shippen, 1754 July 24; 1p.; Hamilton, James, 1710-1783 (Box OS)
    Cover letter for two writs for the sherriffs in Lancaster and York.
  - to James Burd, 1754 July 27; 1p.; McIlvaine, William & David (Box 1)
    Philadelphia. Directions for the sale of cargo, and use of profits.
  - to James Burd, 1754 September 18; 1p.; Bell, John (Box 1)
    Philadelphia. Letter of introduction.
  - to James Burd, 1754 October 19; 1p.; Blyth, William (Box 1)
    Carlisle. Regarding sending Burd's horse.
  - to James Burd, 1755 February 14; 1p.; Groves, John (Box 1)
    Philadelphia. Replies to Burd, comments on not having sword or pistols.
  - to James Burd, 1755 March 1; 1p.; Polson, John (Box 1)
    Answers in reply for his brother. Comments on the horse Serg. Finlay rode, and not meeting John Bartam.
  - to James Burd, 1755 March 4; 1p.; Maxwell, William, 1733?-1796 (Box 1)
    Discusses the sending of flour in the township.
  - to James Burd, 1755 March 17; 2pp.; Hoops, Adam (Box 1)
  - to Edward Shippen, 1755 April 10; 1p.; Hamilton, James, 1710-1783 (Box 1)
    Regarding land he has available.
  - to James Burd, et al., 1755 May 8; 1p.; Shippen, Edward (Box 1)
    Lancaster. Recommendation for the bearer, Joseph Piper to clear the road.
  - to Edward Shippen, 1755 May 10; 1p.; Hamilton, James, 1710-1783 (Box 1)
    Unable to travel due to illness. Discusses a later visit.
  - to James Burd et al., 1755 May 12; 1p.; Atlee, William (Box 1)
    Lancaster. Bearers of letter wait to work on road.
  - to James Burd, et al., 1755 May 12; 1p.; Shippen, Edward (Box 1)
  - to James Burd, 1755 May 23; 1p.; Buchanan and Armstrong (Box 1)
    Recommendation for William White.
  - to James Burd, et al., 1755 May 25; 1p.; Atlee, William (Box 1)
    Lancaster. Sending men to work on the road.
  - to James Burd, etc., 1755 June 5; 1p.; Peters, Richard, 1743-1828 (Box 1)
    Philadelphia. Regarding obtaining guns and powder for Burd's men, and what he should do in the meantime.
  - to the commissioners ... the road, 1755 June 8; 1p.; Buchanan, William (Box 1)
    Carlisle. Recommendation for workmen.
  - to James Burd, et al., 1755 June 8; 1p.; Buchanan, William (Box 1)
  - to the commissioners ... the road, 1755 June 11; 1p.; Buchanan, William (Box 1)
  - to James Burd, 1755 June 18; 1p.; Hoops, Adam (Box 1)
    Delay sending the wagons. Situation in the camp.
  - to James Burd, 1755 June 24; 1p.; Byers, John (Box 1)
    Lack of bread and flour.
  - to James Burd, 1755 July 8; 1p.; Burd, Sarah Shippen, 1731-1784 (Box 1)
    Shippensburg. Cover for sending two letters (not included) from the Governor and Mr. Kidd. Comments on the family.
  - to James Burd, 1755 August 27; 1p.; West, Frances (Box 1)
    Carlisle. Note on account for three axes.
  - to James Burd, 1755 September 17; 1p.; Polson, John (Box 1)
    Fort Cumberland. Note regarding paying an account..
  - to unknown correspondent, 1755 October 31; 2pp.; Hamilton, James, 1710-1783 (Box 1)
    Regarding a petition from the inhabitants of Lancaster regarding their defense, and Hamilton's decision to go there.
  - to Edward Shippen, 1755 November 24; 2pp.; Hamilton, James, 1710-1783 (Box 1)
    Replies to Shippen's letter regarding the defense of Lancaster, and the establishment of forts using his timber.
  - to Edward Shippen, 1755 December 13; 1p.; Hamilton, James, 1710-1783 (Box 1)
    Reply to Shippen's letters. Comments on the situation in Lancaster.
  - to James Burd, et al., 1755; 1p.; Buchanan, William (Box 1)
    Carlisle. Gentlemen sent to work on the road.
  - to James Burd, et al., 1755; 1p.; Shippen, Edward (Box 1)
    Lancaster. Gentleman sent to work on the road.
  - to James Burd, 1755 Tuesday; 1p.; Trent, William (Box 1)
    Note regarding a Frenchman not having information.
  - to the inhabitants of Cumberland County, 1755; 1p.; Croghan, George, d.1782 (Box 1)
    Aughick. An Indian spy was captured near fort at Aughick. Freeman and Smith 2725.
  - to George Croghan, 1756 March 9; 1p.; Clark, Daniel (Box 1)
    Carlisle. Notice of payment necessary to cover purchase of needed clothing for troops.
  - to James Burd, 1756 March 10; 2pp.; Buchanan, William (Box 1)
    Carlisle. Regarding the building of the road, and Buchanan's opinions.
  - to Thomas Clark and James Burd, 1756 March 24; 1p.; Brown, James (Box 1)
    Request for pay to George Dougherty.
  - to Capt. Potter, 1756 March 24; 1p.; Machan, John (Box 1)
    Request for pay.
  - to James Burd, 1756 April 25; 1p.; McLaughlin, Alexander (Box 1)
    Fort Granville. Request for payment to me.
  - to James Burd, 1756 May 20; 1p.; Ward, Edward (Box 1)
    Fort Granville. Situation of garrison, waiting for instructions.
  - to Mr. Clark, 1756 June 3; 1p.; Alrichs, H. (Box 1)
    Carlisle. Determining some qualified officers.
  - to James Burd, 1756 June 7; 1p.; Armstrong, John (Box 1)
    Carlisle. Acknowledges receiving material, unsure of it.
  - to James Burd, 1756 June 28; 1p.; Allen, James (Box 1)
    Carlisle. Note regarding his health and willingness to serve.
  - to Edward Shippen, 1756 July 6; 2pp.; Hamilton, James, 1710-1783 (Box 1)
    Regarding the accounts for the supplies.
  - Receipt to Capt. James Young, 1756 July 14; 1p. (Box 1)
    For pay.
  - to James Hamilton, 1756 August 14; 3pp.; Shippen, Edward (Box 1)
    Lancaster. Comments on business matters of Hamilton. Reports of French and Indians building a road, as well as other conditions in the area.
  - to James Burd, 1756 September 7; 2pp.; Clapham, William (Box 1)
    Fort Augusta. Initial and additional marching orders for Burd from Fort Augusta to Hunter's Fort.
  - to Mr. Harris, 1756 October 18; 1p.; Elder, John (Box 1)
    Paxton. Request for pay due his servant.
  - to the Court Martial, 1756 November 28; 1p.; Bostick, John (Box 1)
    Fort Hallifax. Testimony for the court.
  - to James Burd, 1756 December 23; 1p.; Mercer, Hugh, 1726-1777 (Box 1)
    Fort Morris. Part of letter missing, rest states no Indians have been sighted.
  - Testimony, 1756; 1p.; Clark, Daniel (Box 1)
    Testimony regarding Mr. Bryan being confined to his tent.
  - to James Burd, 1757 February 9; 1p.; Espey, Thomas (Box 2)
    Fragment missing. Discusses money and supplies.
  - to James Burd, 1757 February 18; 1p.; Clapham, William (Box 2)
    Burd's orders regarding the expiration of enlistments of soldiers.
  - to unknown correspondent, 1757 March 11; 2pp.; Morgan, John (Box 2)
    Fort at Hunter's. Situation of the sick under his care since the hospital was moved.
  - to James Burd, 1757 March 27; 1p.; Forester, Thomas (Box 2)
    Regarding wages of Mathew Coltray (?).
  - to John Hambright, 1757 April 11; 1p.; Thompson, Robert (Box 2)
    Lancaster. Regarding a letter for Col. Weiser, and a dog which was stolen from Thompson.
  - Affidavit, 1757 April 30; 1p.; Coltrap, Mathew (Box 2)
    Statement of service.
  - to Edward Shippen, 1757 April; 1p.; Hamilton, James, 1710-1783 (Box 2)
    Requests the he and his sons accompany him.
  - to Dr. Thomson, 1757 April; 1p.; Weiser, Conrad (Box 2)
    States the situation of his battalion and his inability to send reinforcements.
  - to James Burd, 1757 May 2; 1p.; Burd, Sarah Shippen, 1731-1784 (Box 2)
    Lancaster. Personal letter, regarding return of her brother. Comments on her father not returning yet.
  - to James Burd, 1757 May 2; 1p.; Work, Patrick (Box 2)
    Fort Hallifax. Reinforcements for the garrison have not arrived. Comments on Corporal Robertson.
  - to James Burd, 1757 May 9; 1p.; Croker, John (Box 2)
    Fort Augusta. Requests permission to return home to handle some affairs.
  - to James Burd, 1757 May 15; 1p.; Ingel, Andrew (Box 2)
    Reading. Sending soldier to collect his papers and cloth.
  - to James Burd, 1757 June 1; 1p.; Atlee, Samuel John, 1739-1786 (Box 2)
    Fort Hallifax. Situation at the garrison.
  - to James Burd, 1757 June 6; 1p; Galbreath, Bartram (Box 2)
    Fort Hunter. Danger of Indian attack while Fort Hunter is short of men. Freeman and Smith 2739.
  - to James Burd, 1757 June 18; 2pp.; Clark, Daniel (Box 2)
    Carlisle. French and Indian raid parties at Colonel Dunbar's old camp. French and Indians have road from Albany. Indians at Shippensburg. Freeman and Smith 1371.
  - to James Burd, 1757 June 19; 1p.; Miller, Isaac (Box 2)
    Shippensburg. Inability to return to work because of weather and the enemy. Intends to in order to repay bond.
  - to James Burd, 1757 June 30; 1p.; Work, Patrick (Box 2)
    Harris's Ferry. Has arrived with men, his orders from the governor regarding marching.
  - to James Burd, 1757 August 9; 1p.; Lloyd, Thomas (Box 2)
    Philadelphia. Gov. Delancey of New York on march with militia to relieve Fort William Henry, infested with French, Canadians, and Indians. Freeman and Smith 1374.
  - to James Burd, 1757 August 15; 1p.; Work, Patrick (Box 2)
    Fort Hallifax. Condition of soldiers in the garrison, shortage of provisions, and complaints regarding not receiving rum ration.
  - to James Burd, 1757 September 16; 1p.; Work, Patrick (Box 2)
    Fort Hallifax. Efforts taken to supply garrison with beef.
  - to James Burd, 1757 November 1; 2pp.; Lloyd, Thomas (Box 2)
    Philadelphia. Has lost his wife to small pox, is awaiting the return of the governor from New Castle to provide him orders.
  - to James Hamilton, 1757 December 13; 2pp.; Shippen, Edward (Box 2)
    Lancaster. Comments on the execution of deeds. Informs Hamilton of Col. Hanwix's men cutting down his timber for fire wood.
  - to James Burd, 1757; 1p.; Steel, John (Box 2)
    Discusses ability to work.
  - to James Burd, 1758 January 10; 1p.; Jameson, David (Box 2)
    Paxton. Snow prevented him sending batteaux. Sighting of Indian scouts.
  - to Capt. Weatherholt, 1758 February 3; 2pp.; D.W. (Box 2)
    Philadelphia. Discusses enemy Munsey Indians on information from a friendly Indian. Freeman and Smith 2336.
  - to James Burd, 1758 May 4; 1p.; Craghead, George (Box 2)
    Fort Henry. Discusses being at the Fort, and condition of the men to take field.
  - to James Burd, 1758 May 11; 2pp.; Peters, Richard, 1743-1828 (Box 2)
    Philadelphia. Letter of introduction for Mr. Heidler to be Capt. Gambright's ensign. Has worked at Woolwich Informs him of Capt. Shippen's promotion to Major.
  - to James Burd, 1758 May 16; 2pp.; Shippen, Edward (Box 2)
    Delay in sending a batteaux. Has hear he will be coming down.
  - to James Burd, 1758 May 29; 2pp.; Shippen, Edward (Box 2)
    Lancaster. Sending him extract of letter from Major Shippen. Comments on Mr. Bard's passing through.
  - to James Burd, 1758 June 5; 1p.; Hosterman, Jacob (Box 2)
    Lancaster. Asks for the appraisal of his cattle.
  - to Henry Bouquet, 1758 June 8; 1p.; Callendar, Robert (Box 2)
    Fort Loudoun. Discharged wagons, comments on road work.
  - to James Burd, 1758 August 25; 1p.; Bouquet, Henry, 1719-1765 (Box 2)
    Is to send men to assist in opening the mountain so the road can continue.
  - to James Burd, 1758 September 29; 1p.; Singleton, John. (Box 2)
    Regarding lack of pay, and need to return home to settle affairs.
  - to James Burd, 1758 October 5; 1p.; Garraway, Charles (Box 2)
    Philadelphia. Is awaiting orders to return to the army from Governor Denny.
  - to R. Harding, 1758 October 13; 1p.; Hubbard, Edward (Box 2)
    Orders to take force and reconnoiter a small band party of enemy.
  - to James Burd, 1758 October 13; 1p.; Singleton, John. (Box 2)
    Unable to go with party.
  - to James Burd, 1758 November 30; 1p.; Halkett, Francis (Box 2)
    Pittsburgh. Wishes listed belongings to be sent.
  - to James Burd, 1758 December 1; 2pp.; Bouquet, Henry, 1719-1765 (Box 2)
    Late Fort Duquesne. Orders for men not to proceed unless ordered by the general. Comments on Capt. Tomson.
  - to James Burd, 1758; 1p.; Lander, Francis (Box 2)
    Reply on why he has not performed his duty.
  - to James Burd, 1758; 1p.; Lloyd, Thomas (Box 2)
    Can not proceed due to lack of forage.
  - to James Burd, 1759 March 6; 1p.; Shavver, Abraham (Box 2)
    Inquiring about his discharge, and money spent.
  - to James Burd, 1759 May 8; 1p. [fragment]; Keon, Jacob (Box 2)
    Lancaster. Part of letter missing. Discusses recruiting in Lancaster.
  - to James Burd, 1759 May 9; 1p.; Clark, John (Box 2)
    Promotion of Robert Lowry, and sent Scott Beating to Philadelphia.
  - to James Burd, 1759 June 8; 2pp.; Bouguet, Henry (Box 2)
    Philadelphia. Comments on difficulties getting pay for men in the service, and the assembly not assisting the general.
  - to James Burd, 1759 June 16; 1p.; Kern, Jacob (Box 2)
    Reading. Situation of men and recruiting.
  - to Meager Jameson, 1759 June 22; 1p.; Colthrop, Mathew (Box 2)
    Carlisle. Asks for money for his wife.
  - to James Young, 1759 July 10; 1p.; McKee, Daniel (Box 2)
    Lancaster. Request for pay after discharge.
  - to unidentified correspondent, 1759 July 10; 1p.; McKnight, William (Box 2)
  - to James Burd, 1759 July 11; 1p.; McKnight, George (Box 2)
    Fort Bedford. Concerning the command of Capt. Jones' company following his death.
  - to James Young, 1759 July 19; 1p.; McCallister, John (Box 2)
  - to James Burd, 1759 August 29; 1p.; Jones, John (Box 2)
    Fort Bedford. Notice he has arrived at fort and request for supplies.
  - to James Burd, 1759 September 10; 1p.; Livingston, James (Box 2)
    Cumberland. Regarding the apprehension of deserters..
  - to James Burd, 1759 October 4; 2pp.; Unidentified correspondent (Box 2)
    Pittsburgh. Request for batteaux..
  - to Ensign Menzes, 1759 October 7; 2pp.; Unknown (Box 2)
    Sending man and axe to help build raft to ferry sheep.
  - to Joseph Shippen, 1759 October 26; 2pp.; Shippen, Edward (Box 2)
    Lancaster. Replies to Joseph's letter received.
  - to Ratchford Duffield, 1759 November 2; 1p.; Burd, James (Box 2)
    Sending supplies, orders for building bridges.
  - to Joseph Shippen, 1759 November 4; 1p.; Burd, James (Box 2)
    Going to Pittsburgh, advices brother on what to do.
  - to Joseph Shippen, 1759 November 17; 1p.; Shippen, Edward (Box 2)
    Lancaster. Discusses the appointment of judges. [fragments missing].
  - List of Magistrates for the County of Lancaster, 1759 November 17; 1p. (Box 2)
    Names of magistrates in Lancaster County.
  - to James Hamilton, 1759 November 26; 3pp.; Shippen, Edward (Box 2)
    Lancaster. Comments on lots in Lancaster that are of interest to builders, informs the governor of his service to the army, and the work of Col. Burd and his son Joseph.
  - to Joseph Shippen, 1759 December 3; 1p.; Burd, James (Box 2)
    Fort London. Plans to go to Lancaster, comments on condition of location.
  - to Joseph Shippen, 1759 December 6; 1p.; Bullitt, Thomas (Box 2)
    Reminds of favor regarding sword.
  - to James Burd, 1759 December 6; 1p.; Mather, Capt. (Box 2)
    Shippensburg. Sends favor of newspapers, comments on dinner had last summer at Widow Grey's.
  - to Joseph Shippen, 1759 December 8; 1p.; Shippen, Edward (Box 2)
    Lancaster. Where he will be stationed during the winter..
  - to Joseph Shippen, 1759 December 10; 2pp. [fragments missing]; Armstrong, John (Box 2)
    Fort Ligonier. Dispute over the surgeon's tour.
  - to James Burd, 1759 December 11; 1p.; Jameson, David (Box 2)
    Pittsburgh. Condition of garrison, lack of supplies.
  - to Joseph Shippen, 1759 December 12; 1p.; Armstrong, John (Box 2)
    Ligonier. Additional comments on need of a surgeon.
  - to Joseph Shippen, 1759 December 13; 1p.; Ourry, Lewis, 1717-1779 (Box 2)
    Fort Bradford. Trouble obtaining horses.
  - to Joseph Shippen, 1759 December 14; 1p.; Brodhead, Charles (Box 2)
    Pittsburgh. Sending men unfit for duty, asks for pass.
  - to Joseph Shippen, 1759 December 15; 1p.; Brodhead, Charles (Box 2)
    Pittsburgh. Acknowledges receiving orders, and comments on the disposition of his men.
  - to Joseph Shippen, 1759 December 15; 1p.; Ourry, Lewis, 1717-1779 (Box 2)
    Fort Bedford. Guard request in light of marching orders.
  - to James Burd, 1759 December 17; 1p.; Hamilton, James, 1710-1783 (Box 2)
    Philadelphia. Orders for the discharge of men.
  - to Joseph Shippen, 1759 December 18; 2pp.; Burd, James (Box 2)
    Lancaster. Comments on the future of the battalion, and lack of news from Philadelphia; the situation with Col. Work; and packages sent.
  - to Joseph Shippen, 1759 December 18; 1p.; Jameson, David (Box 2)
    Pittsburgh. Explains the differences in the returns for men in the 2nd Battalion.
  - to Joseph Shippen, 1759 December 18; 2pp.; Jameson, David (Box 2)
    Pittsburgh. Just received letter after sending previous. Comments on return of men. Mentions a scheme regarding the command of the Pennsylvania regiment given by Captain Mathers.
  - to Joseph Shippen, 1759 December 19; 1p.; Potter James (Box 2)
    Inquires whether he should come to Bedford, and why he has not.
  - to Joseph Shippen, 1759 December 22; 1p.; Brodhead, Charles (Box 2)
    Pittsburgh. Comments on return of men, and the rumored discharge.
  - to Joseph Shippen, 1759 December 25; 1p.; Armstrong, John (Box 2)
    Fort Loudon. Received order regarding discharge, comments on how it complicates the general's orders.
  - to James Shippen, 1759 December 25; 1p.; Ensign Curchod (Box 2)
    Stoney Creek. Sending men, and needs replacements.
  - to James Shippen, 1759 December 25; 1p.; Hunter, Samuel (Box 2)
    Fort Littleton. Report after being relieved and his intensions..
  - to James Young, 1759 December 26; 1p.; Miller, Isaac (Box 2)
    Pay request for discharge.
  - to Joseph Shippen, 1759 December 26; 2pp.; Shippen, Edward (Box 2)
    Lancaster. Personal letter metions Christmas dinner, and missing him. Comments on the discharge of troops.
  - to Joseph Shippen, 1759 December 26; 1p.; Scott, Joseph (Box 2)
    Shippensburg. Situation at the post, mentions news of discharge.
  - to Joseph Shippen, 1759 December 28; 1p.; Campbell, Francis (Box 2)
    Notes on obtaining forage.
  - to Joseph Shippen, 1759 December 29; 2pp.; Burd, James (Box 2)
    Lancaster. Informs him what is to happen to the battalion.
  - to James Burd, 1759 December 29; 1p.; Jameson, David (Box 2)
    Fort Ligonier. Informs him of the situation regarding the Virginia Regiment taking over the garrisons.
  - to Joseph Shippen, 1759 December 31; 1p.; Blair, John (Box 2)
    Fort Loudon. Supplies sent.
  - to James Burd, 1759 December 31; 1p.; Orndt, Jacob (Box 2)
    Fort Augusta. Leave for Mr. Johnson, and notes conduct of Ensign Adam Henry.
  - to James Burd, 1759; 1p.; Price, Samuel (Box 2)
    Notes taking a deserter from his company.
  - to James Burd, 1759; 1p.; West, Francis (Box 2)
    Regarding payment.
  - to James Young, 1760 January 5; 1p.; Scott, William (Box 3)
    Fort Bedford. Request for pay.
  - to Joseph Shippen, 1760 January 7; 1p.; Scott, Joseph (Box 3)
    Shippensburg. Returned to post awaiting discharge.
  - to Joseph Shippen, 1760 January 10; 1p.; Baird, Jno. (Box 3)
    Fort Littleton. Copy of Col. Armstrong's letter regarding collecting arms, and a request for instructions.
  - to Joseph Shippen, 1760 January 11; 1p.; Little, John (Box 3)
    Fort Junyata. Sending copy of Col Armstrong's letter regarding collecting arms.
  - to Joseph Shippen, 1760 January 13; 1p.; Baird, Jno. (Box 3)
    Fort Lyttleton. Marching of Royal Americans, and requests direction concerning arms at the garrison.
  - to Joseph Shippen, 1760 January 14; 1p.; Little, John (Box 3)
    Acknowledges receving orders, and comments on the flat.
  - to Evan Anderson, 1760 February 2; 1p.; Gerringer, Henery (Box 3)
  - to Evan Anderson, 1760 February 2; 1p.; Shale, George (Box 3)
  - to Evan Anderson, 1760 February 2; 1p.; Shireman, Peter (Box 3)
  - to James Burd, 1760 February 7; 2pp.; unknown correspondent (Box 3)
    Lancaster. Instructions on planting an orchard.
  - to James Young, 1760 March 14; 1p.; Ellis, John (Box 3)
    Lancaster. Request for pay.
  - to unknown, 1760 April 17; 1p.; unknown correspondent (Box 3)
    Philadelphia. Note on the bill passing to pay for a battalion. "discharged account John Lukins".
  - to James Burd, 1760 April 30; 1p.; Howard, George Towen (Box 3)
    Lancaster. Asks for justice being in guard house for improperly enlisting a soldier.
  - to James Burd, 1760 May 25; 2pp.; Young, James (Box 3)
    Philadelphia. Comment on Capt. Nelson leaving without supplies. Regarding preparations for assembling at Carlisle.
  - to unknown, 1760 May 29; 1p.; Neilson, Samuel (Box 3)
    Carlisle. Notes lack of weapons and equipment for men.
  - to James Burd, 1760 June 3; 1p.; Garraway, Charles (Box 3)
    Philadelphia. Inquiry about James McCally.
  - to James Burd, 1760 June 25; 1p.; Ourry, Lewis, 1717-1779 (Box 3)
    Fort Bedford. Supplies he has for Burd, notes other officers arriving and departing.
  - to James Burd, 1760 August 3; 1p.; Miles, Samuel, 1740-1805 (Box 3)
    Vinango. Asks assistance in getting a soldier properly mustered.
  - to James Burd, 1760 August 17; 1p.; Gibson, James (Box 3)
    Bushy Run. Inquiry regarding soldier from company without a pass.
  - to Col. Bouquet, 1760 August 31; 2pp. [fragments missing]; Burd, James (Box 3)
    Fort Pitt. Requests certificate from Bouquet regarding pay, comments on location or news of other officers.
  - to John Ormsby, 1760 September 1; 1p.; Metcalf, John (Box 3)
    Carlisle. Receipt for cattle..